Register of the George I. Duca Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
George I. Duca papers,
1819-1985
75085
Duca, George I., 1905-
107 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 1 envelope, 4 phonotape reels (45.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Diaries, correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, and photographs, relating to Romanian foreign policy and politics in the twentieth century, and to the Romanian royal family. Also available on microfilm (89 reels).
Administrative Information
Access
Originals closed. Microfilm available for use.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat to find the full extent of the collection.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Also available on Microfilm (89 reels).
Biographical Note
1905 Born
1928-1947 Romanian diplomat; held various diplomatic posts, including in Tokyo, Rio de Janeiro, and Washington, D.C.
1939-1942 Recalled to Bucharest, he was appointed Assistant Chief of the Political Division of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
1942 November While chargé d'affaires in Finland, Duca met informally with some close American friends who worked at the U.S. embassy in Stockholm. During their discussions, Duca informed them of Romania's willingness to break its alliance with the Nazis. He then reported these discussions to King Michael and to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
1943 August - 1947 While assigned to the Romanian legation in Sweden, he was asked by the leaders of the democratic opposition parties and King Michael to secretly contact the U.S. embassy and let it know of their plans to overthrow Romania's fascist government, led by Ion Antonescu
1944 Duca carried out negotiations with both the American and Soviet embassies until the coup on August 23, when King Michael proclaimed that Romania was joining the allied forces
1947 Moved to the United States Got involved in the relief movement for new Romanian refugees
1954 Became an American citizen Active with relief work as Secretary of the Romanian Welfare in New York
1958-1967 Lecturer as a member of the International PEN Club, whose cover he used for his work for the Free Europe Committee and for the Assembly of Captive European Nations (which he represented in Japan)
1961-1975 Executive Director of Alliances Françaises, United States
1975-1985 Part-time lecturer and student advisor at Stanford University Helped build the Romanian collections of the Hoover Institution Archives on the Stanford campus
1982-1985 Contributor, Radio Free Europe
1985 November 17 Died
Scope and Content Note
After 30 years of self-imposed exile, George Duca, a former Romanian diplomat, said: "My Romania has disappeared and never will be alive again" (San Francisco Examiner, May 2, 1978, "The Monarchist Who Lost All: At 72, He's a Winner" by Peter King). Trying to recreate "his" Romania, he built a small island in the Hoover Archives: an invaluable research collection on Romanian modern history. Between 1975 and 1985, he donated to the archives the private papers of his father (former Prime Minister of Romania) and of almost fifty of his friends and collaborators, former politicians, diplomats and writers.
George Duca's papers consist mainly of 120 notebooks of his diary (of significant importance are those from 1914-1949); his correspondence with various royal figures (including Queen Marie, Princess Ileana, and Queen Helen of Romania,), his family (including his father, Ion Duca), and Romanian émigré leaders; his memoirs, Cronica unui Român in veacul XX, including an English translation, and his reports from Japan (where he worked for the Free Europe Committee, under the cover of the International PEN Club) to the Free Europe Committee and the Assembly of Captive European Nations (see Career file, box 98).
George Duca's collection also contains a large number of remarkable prints. Among them, hundreds depicting members of the Romanian royal family, which constitute one of the most impressive photographic collections regarding the Romanian royal family abroad. These are to be found not only in the PHOTOGRAPHS series, but also in the DIARIES series.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Marie, Queen, consort of Ferdinand I, King of Romania, 1875-1938.; Romania.; Romania--Court and courtiers.; Romania--Foreign relations.; Romania--Politics and government--1914-1944.
Occupations
Diplomats--Romania.
Genres and Forms of Material
Phonotapes.
Series Description
- Biographical File, 1915-1985. (Box 1-5)
  Bibliography, biography, decorations and awards, financial papers, identity papers, medical records, mementos, military papers, naturalization papers, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Diaries, 1916-1985. (Box 6-61)
  Holograph diaries arranged chronologically. Includes typewritten transcripts for 1962-1985
- Correspondence, 1909-1985. (Box 62-85)
  Correspondence arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
- Speeches and Writings, 1951-1985. (Box 86-97)
  Articles, plays, books and notes, arranged chronologically by title
- Career File, 1943-1985. (Box 98-100)
  Correspondence, notes, reports, and miscellaneous documents, arranged alphabetically by name of the organization George Duca was affiliated with
- Subject File, 1819-1985. (Box 101-103)
  Notes, letters, books, drawings, arranged alphabetically by subject
- Photographs, 1890-1985. (Box 104-108 and photo file)
  Prints and negatives depicting mainly members of the Hohenzollern family
- Oversize Materials, 1819-1934. (Box 109)
  Documents, drawings, and newspaper issues pertaining to the history of Romania
- Phonotapes, 1961-1971. (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
  Four phonotapes, mainly of interviews of George Duca
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1915-1985
  - General (Box 1)
    - 1915-1924 (Folder 1: 1)
    - 1916-1918 (Folder 1: 2)
    - 1920s (Folder 1: 3)
    - 1930s (Folder 1: 4)
  - Bibliography, 1933-1985 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Biography (projected) of George Duca, by B. Crystal and B. Lapin, 1982 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Decorations and awards, 1932-1943. (Folder 1: 7)
    Includes a decree signed by Michael I, King of Romania, for the nomination of George Duca as a Comandor of the Crown of Romania Order and a document bestowing the Apostolic benedictions of Pope John Paul II to George Duca
  - Financial papers, 1917-1985. (Box-folder 2: 1-5)
    Includes income tax documents
  - Genealogical papers (Folder 2: 6)
  - Identity papers (passports, miscellaneous certificates, birth certificate, Social Security documents) (Box-folder 3: 1-3)
  - Medical records (insurance and open-heart surgery records) (Folder 3: 4-5)
  - Mementos. "Personal souvenirs" (such as Romanian banknotes from the beginning of the 20th century, and a guest book from the Maldaresti estate, 1920-1921) (Folder 3: 6-8)
  - Naturalization papers (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Register of correspondence (Folder 4: 2-4)
  - Subject file
    - Exhibit of George Duca's diaries at the Hoover Institution, 1979 (Folder 4: 5)
    - Foreign trips (Box 5)
      - Greece, 1932 (Folder 5: 1)
      - Israel, 1974-1975 (Folder 5: 2)
      - Italy, 1982 (Folder 5: 3)
    - Military service, 1924-1925, 1931 (Folder 5: 4)
    - Real estate
      - United States - Kingscote Gardens on Stanford Campus, California (Folder 5: 5)
    - School years (Folder 5: 6)
  - Will (Folder 5: 7)
- DIARIES, 1916-1985 (Box 6)
  - Holographs
    - 1916-1917 (Folder 6: 1)
    - 1919-1920 (Folder 6: 2)
    - 1920-1922 (Folder 6: 3)
    - 1922-1924 (Folder 6: 4)
    - 1924-1925 (Folder 7: 1)
    - 1925-1926
      - Volume I (Folder 7: 2)
      - Volume II (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - 1926-1927 (Folder 8: 2)
      - Volume I
      - Volume II (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - 1927-1928 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - 1928-1929 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - 1929 (Folder 11: 2)
    - 1929-1930 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - 1930 (Folder 12: 2)
    - 1931-1932 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - 1933 (Box-folder 15: 1)
      - Volume I
      - Volume II (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - 1933-1934. (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
      Includes notes related to the assassination of Ion G. Duca
    - 1934-1935 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - 1936-1937 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - 1937 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - 1937-1938 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - 1938-1939. (Box-folder 22: 1)
      Includes photos from the funeral of Marie, Queen of Romania
    - 1939-1940. (Box-folder 23: 1)
      Includes photos of Michael I, King of Romania
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 23: 2)
    - 1942-1943 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - 1943-1944 (Box-folder 25: 1)
      - Diary
      - Appendix (Folder 25: 2)
      - Loose material (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - 1944-1945 (Folder 26: 2)
    - 1945-1946 (Box-folder 27: 1)
      - Diary
      - Appendix (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - 1946-1947 (Folder 29: 1)
    - 1947-1948 (Box-folder 30: 1)
    - 1948-1949 (Folder 30: 2)
    - 1949-1950 (Box-folder 31: 1)
    - 1951-1952 (Box-folder 32: 1)
    - 1952-1953 (Box-folder 33: 1)
    - 1953-1955 (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - 1955-1956 (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - 1956-1957 (Box-folder 36: 1)
    - 1957-1958 (Box-folder 37: 1)
    - 1959-1960 (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - 1960-1961 (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - 1961-1962 (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - 1962-1963 (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - 1963-1964 (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - 1964-1965 (Box-folder 43: 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Box-folder 44: 1)
    - 1966-1967 (Box-folder 45: 1)
    - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 48: 1)
    - 1969 (Folder 48: 2)
    - 1970-1971 (Box-folder 49: 1)
    - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - 1972-1973 (Box-folder 51: 1)
    - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 53: 1)
    - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 54: 1)
    - 1977-1978 (Box-folder 55: 1)
    - 1979-1980 (Folder 56: 1)
    - 1980-1981 (Box-folder 57: 1)
    - 1982-1983 (Box-folder 58: 1)
    - 1983-1984 (Box-folder 59: 1)
    - 1984-1985 (Box-folder 60: 1)
  - Typewritten transcripts (Box 61)
    - 1962-1973 (Folder 61: 1)
    - 1974-1980 (Folder 61: 2)
    - 1980-1983 (Folder 61: 3)
    - 1983-1985 (Folder 61: 4)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1909-1985 (Box 62)
  - General
    - General
      - 1923 (Folder 62: 1)
      - 1924 (Folder 62: 2)
      - 1925 (Folder 62: 3)
      - 1926 (Folder 62: 4)
      - 1927 (Folder 62: 5-6)
      - 1928 (Box-folder 63: 1-2)
      - 1929 (Folder 63: 3-4)
      - 1930 (Folder 63: 5-6)
      - 1931 (Box-folder 64: 1-3)
      - 1932 (Folder 64: 4-5)
      - 1934 (Folder 64: 6)
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 64: 7)
      - 1943 (Folder 64: 8)
      - 1944 (Folder 64: 9)
      - 1944-1945 (Box-folder 65: 1)
      - 1945 (Folder 65: 2)
      - 1946 (Folder 65: 3)
      - 1946-1947 (Folder 65: 4)
      - 1947-1948 (Folder 65: 5)
      - 1948 (Folder 65: 6)
      - 1949 (Folder 65: 7)
      - 1949-1950 (Folder 65: 8)
      - 1951 (Folder 65: 9)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 66: 1)
      - 1952-1953 (Folder 66: 2)
      - 1953 (Folder 66: 3)
      - 1954 (Folder 66: 4)
      - 1955 (Folder 66: 5)
      - 1956 (Folder 66: 6)
      - 1957 (Folder 66: 7)
      - 1958-1959 (Folder 66: 8)
      - 1959 (Folder 66: 9)
      - 1960 (Folder 67: 1)
      - 1961-1962 (Folder 67: 2)
      - 1962 (Folder 67: 3)
      - 1964 (Folder 67: 4)
      - 1964-1965 (Folder 67: 5)
      - 1965-1966 (Folder 67: 6)
      - 1966-1967 (Folder 67: 7)
      - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 68: 1)
      - 1968 (Folder 68: 2-3)
      - 1969 (Folder 68: 4-5)
      - 1970 (Folder 68: 6-7)
      - 1971 (Folder 68: 8-9)
      - 1972 (Folder 68: 10-11)
      - 1973 (Folder 68: 12-13)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 69: 1-2)
      - 1975 (Folder 69: 3-4)
      - 1975-1979 (Folder 69: 5)
      - 1976 (Folder 69: 6)
      - 1977 (Box-folder 69: 7-8)
      - 1978 (Box-folder 70: 1-2)
      - 1978-1979 (Folder 70: 3)
      - 1979 (Box-folder 71: 1-2)
      - 1980 (Folder 71: 3-4)
      - 1980 (Box-folder 72: 1)
      - 1981 (Folder 72: 2-4)
      - 1982 (Folder 72: 5-6)
      - 1982 (Box-folder 73: 1-2)
      - 1983 (Folder 73: 3-7)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 74: 1-4)
      - 1985 (Folder 74: 5)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 75: 1-2)
    - Concerning George Duca's collaboration with and separation from W. S. Wasserman (Box-folder 76: 1)
    - Concerning George Duca's collaboration with Tricolorul, 1981-1983 (Folder 76: 2)
    - Concerning Terence Elsberry's book Marie of Romania: The Intimate Life of a Twentieth Century Queen. (Folder 76: 3)
      Includes other materials
    - Concerning Hannah Pakula's book The Last Romantic, 1934-1985 (Folder 76: 4)
    - With various family members, not specifically mentioned below, 1903-1919 (Folder 76: 5)
    - With various royal figures, not specifically mentioned below, 1940s and 1960s (Folder 76: 6)
    - With various teachers, 1922-1932 (Folder 76: 7)
  - Unidentified ("Excerpts from letters from a friend") (Folder 77: 1)
  - Alexandra, Mother (Ileana, Princess of Romania, Archduchess of Austria)
    - 1924-1927 (Folder 77: 2)
    - 1928-1940 (Folder 77: 3-5)
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 77: 6)
    - 1942-1948 (Folder 77: 7)
    - 1949 (Box-folder 78: 1)
    - 1950-1955 (Folder 78: 2)
    - 1956-1960 (Folder 78: 3)
    - 1961-1962 (Folder 78: 4)
    - 1963-1965 (Folder 78: 5)
    - 1966-1970 (Folder 78: 6)
    - 1971-1985 (Folder 78: 7)
  - Bibesco, Martha, Princess, 1925-1973 (Box-folder 79: 1)
  - Braescu, Marie, 1960-1968 (Folder 79: 2)
  - Bratianu, Marc, 1967-1968 (Folder 79: 3)
  - Bruno, Pierro Puccioni, 1956-1983 (Folder 79: 4)
  - Busuioceanu, Andrei, 1985 (Folder 79: 5)
  - Caranfil, C., 1962 (Folder 79: 6)
  - Caranfil, Nicolae, 1945-1946 (Folder 79: 7)
  - Catargi, Nelly, 1954 (Folder 79: 8)
  - Claudel, Reine, 1929-1931 (Folder 79: 9)
  - Cretzianu, Alexandru, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 80: 1)
  - Cretzianu, Jeanne, 1927-1929 (Folder 80: 2)
  - Delavrancea Lahovary, Cella, 1926-1934 (Folder 80: 3)
  - Dominic Pire, Father, 1963-1969 (Folder 80: 4)
  - Duca, Gabrielle (aunt)
    - 1910-1932 (Folder 80: 5-6)
    - 1960 (Folder 80: 7)
  - Duca, Gregoire (uncle), 1960-1970 (Folder 80: 8)
  - Duca, Ion G. (father)
    - 1911-1930 (letters from Ion Duca to George Duca) (Folder 80: 9)
    - 1922-1933 (letters from George Duca to Ion Duca) (Folder 80: 10)
  - Duca, Nadia, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 81: 1)
  - Falcoyano, Alexandra, 1954 (Folder 81: 2)
  - Farcasanu, Mihail, 1952 (Folder 81: 3)
  - Ferdinand-Louis, Prince of Prussia, 1953 (Folder 81: 4)
  - Georgescu, L. and R., 1954 (Folder 81: 5)
  - Ghika, Alexandre, Prince, 1947-1959 (Folder 81: 6-7)
  - Habsburg, Alexandra (Baroness S. Baillou), 1953-1984 (Folder 81: 8)
  - Habsburg, Anton, Archduke, 1950 (Folder 81: 9)
  - Habsburg, Dominik, 1953-1984 (Box-folder 82: 1)
  - Habsburg, Elizabeth (Mrs. F. Sandhofer), 1953-1984 (Folder 82: 2)
  - Habsburg, Margareta (Baroness H. Holzhausen), 1953-1984 (Folder 82: 3)
  - Habsburg, Marie-Ileana
    - 1949-1953 (Folder 82: 4)
    - 1954-1956 (Folder 82: 5)
    - 1957-1959 (Folder 82: 6)
  - Habsburg, Stefan and Jerrine
    - 1949-1984. (Folder 82: 7)
      Includes mostly correspondence with their children
  - Habsburg, Stefan and Jerrine
    - 1949-1950 (Folder 83: 1)
    - 1951-1955 (Folder 83: 2)
    - 1956-1965 (Folder 83: 3)
    - 1966-1973 (Folder 83: 4)
    - 1974-1977 (Folder 83: 5)
    - 1977-1983 (Folder 83: 6)
  - Hategan, ?, 1954 (Folder 83: 7)
  - Helen, Queen, Consort of Carol II of Romania
    - 1940-1964 (Folder 83: 8)
    - 1965-1983 (Folder 83: 9)
  - Hines, William A., 1955 (Box-folder 84: 1)
  - Hiott, Nicolae, 1919-1930 (Folder 84: 2)
  - Horch, Franz, n.d. (Folder 84: 3)
  - Hughes, J. C., 1952 (Folder 84: 4)
  - Kseniia Aleksandrovna, Grand Duchess of Russia, 1950-1960 (Folder 84: 5)
  - Kyra, Princess of Prussia, 1952 (Folder 84: 6)
  - Margareta of Romania, Princess, 1970-1971 (Folder 84: 7)
  - Marie, Queen, Consort of Ferdinand I, King of Romania, 1929-1938 (Folder 84: 8-9)
  - Michael I, King of Romania, 1964 (Box-folder 85: 1)
  - Michell, S. A., 1961 (Folder 85: 2)
  - Mirski Sviatopolk, A., Prince, 1951 (Folder 85: 3)
  - Moruzi, Alexandrine, Princess, 1909-1934 (mother) (Folder 85: 4)
  - Moruzi, Smaranda, Princess, 1913-1925 (grandmother) (Folder 85: 5)
  - Pratt Y Soutzo, Marquis, Ambassador, 1952 (Folder 85: 6)
  - Rice, Elmer, 1956-1958 (Folder 85: 7)
  - Rosetti, Charlotte, 1968 (Folder 85: 8)
  - Rosnovanu, J. R., Princess, 1960-1961 (Folder 85: 9)
  - Seber, Jancu, 1968-1971 (Folder 85: 10)
  - Seeley, J., 1954 (Folder 85: 11)
  - Stirbey family, 1919-1932 (Folder 85: 12)
  - Union of Free Romanians, 1978-1985. (Folder 85: 13)
    Comprises correspondence with Ion Ratiu, including on Viorel Tilea's archive
  - Uytborck, M. U., 1961 (Folder 85: 14)
  - Miscellany (Folder 85: 15-16)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1951-1985 (Box 86)
  - "And So to Spain," n.d. (Folder 86: 1)
    Typescript
  - Article on Michael, King of Romania, n.d. (Folder 86: 2)
    Typescript. Includes clippings on the Romanian royal family
  - "The Big Egg," n.d. (Folder 86: 3)
  - "The Case of Two Poodles," n.d. (Folder 86: 4)
  - "Death in the Afternoon: Peruvian Version," n.d. (Folder 86: 5)
  - "Dinner at Seven-Fifteen," n.d. (Folder 86: 6)
  - "Farewell." n.d. (Folder 86: 7)
  - "Father Had Three Wives," n.d. (Folder 86: 8)
  - "A Fighter For Freedom," n.d. (Folder 86: 9)
  - "Five Monks of Ethos," n.d. (Folder 86: 10)
  - "Here Comes the Bride," n.d. (Folder 86: 11)
  - "Hero Wanted," n.d. (Folder 86: 12)
  - "Lovers' Interlude," n.d.
    - English version (Folder 86: 13)
    - Swedish translation (Folder 86: 14)
  - "Maria Regina," n.d.
    - Typescript
      - "God Even Cannot Make That This Hour Has Not Been, 1918-1919" (Folder 86: 15)
      - "Yes, I Believe I am a Winner in Life" (Folder 86: 16)
      - "The Great Adventure, 1920" (Folder 86: 17)
      - "The Hope of the Country, 1927-1930" (Box-folder 87: 1)
      - "Too Long Was the Sadness, 1930-1936" (Folder 87: 2)
      - "The Little Yellow Crocuses, 1937-1938" (Folder 87: 3)
    - Various materials concerning George Duca's book on the Queen, 1926-1953 (Folder 87: 4-5)
  - Notes, n.d.
    - On all the books read since 1933. (Box-folder 88: 1-8)
      Holograph and typescript
    - On the Bossy papers in the Hoover Institution. (Folder 88: 9)
  - "One Heavenly Party," n.d. (Box-folder 89: 1)
  - "Palm Up-Palm Down: Lights And Shadows Over Tunisia," n.d. (Folder 89: 2)
  - "Poodlepink," n.d. (Folder 89: 3)
  - "Reunion," n.d. (Folder 89: 4)
  - "The Scandinavian Way," n.d. (Folder 89: 5)
  - "Seven and a Half," n.d. (Folder 89: 6)
  - "A Tree in Kenya," n.d. (Folder 89: 7)
  - "Venus Goes on a Holiday," n.d. (Folder 89: 8)
  - "The Wonderous Journey of Master Pippin," n.d. (Folder 89: 9)
  - "The Man to Wear a Crown," 1955-1956. (Folder 89: 10-12)
    Essays on former kings and pretenders. Holograph and correspondence
  - Memorandum on Ion Patroiu, 1984. (Box-folder 90: 1)
  - Cronica unui Român in veacul XX, 1985
    - Miscellaneous notes and correspondence on the chronicle. (Folder 90: 2-8)
      Includes Mircea Eliade's suggestions
    - Typescript (incomplete) (Box 91)
      - Undated (Folder 91: 1)
      - 1905-1919 (Folder 91: 2)
      - 1905-1916 (Folder 91: 3)
      - 1916-1918 (Folder 91: 4-5)
      - 1918-1928 (Folder 91: 6)
      - 1928-1930 (Folder 91: 7)
      - 1930-1932 (Folder 91: 8)
      - 1932-1933 (Folder 91: 9)
      - 1933-1934 (Folder 91: 10)
      - 1934-1937 (Folder 91: 11)
      - 1937-1939 (Folder 91: 12)
      - 1939-1942 (Folder 91: 13)
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 91: 14)
      - 1943-1947 (Folder 91: 15)
      - 1947-1958 (Box-folder 92: 1-2)
      - 1958-1961 (Folder 92: 3-4)
      - 1961-1968 (Folder 92: 5)
      - 1961-1968 (Box-folder 93: 1)
      - 1962-1974 (Folder 93: 2)
      - 1968-1974 (Folder 93: 3-4)
      - 1974-1980 (Folder 93: 5)
      - 1980-1985 (Folder 94: 1)
    - English translation, "The Rest Is Not Silence," 1951-1952. (Box-folder 95: 1-4)
    - English translation, "The Rest Is Not Silence", 1951-1952. (Box-folder 96: 1-2)
    - Correspondence with Ion Dumitru Verlag pertaining to George Duca's and to Ion G. Duca's memoirs, 1950-1985. (Folder 96: 3-4)
      Includes photocopies of some of the photographs chosen for the first two volumes of the Cronica
    - Printed copy. (Box-folder 97: 1-3)
      Three volumes
    - Extracts published in Tricolorul, 1982-1983 (Folder 97: 4)
  - "Regina Maria la Conferinta de Pace de la Versailles," paper, American Romanian Academy of Arts and Sciences, Tenth Annual Convention, Berkeley, California, 1985 May 2-4
    - Correspondence on Duca's involvement in the organization of the conference (Folder 97: 5)
    - Papers by Jacques Vergotti (Ion Antonescu), Alexandru Bratu (on Communist discrimination in Romania), and Liviu Floda (Folder 97: 6-8)
    - Printed copy, Lupta, 1985 August 1 (Folder 97: 9)
- CAREER FILE, 1943-1985 (Box 98)
  - Alliances Françaises, United States, 1966-1970. (Folder 98: 1)
    Includes correspondence pertaining to Duca's series of conferences in West Africa, 1969
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, 1972-1985. (Folder 98: 2)
    Includes Duca's correspondence
  - International PEN Club, Center of Writers in Exile, 1958-1967
    - Correspondence and other materials on Duca's mission to Japan, Taiwan, and the Philippines, 1958-1961 (Folder 98: 3)
    - Letters from Japanese students and professors, 1959-1967 (Folder 98: 4-6)
    - Reports by George Duca from Japan to the Assembly of Captive European Nations, New York, 1959-1961 (Folder 98: 7)
    - Reports by George Duca to the Free Europe Committee, 1958-1961 (Folder 98: 8)
  - Radio Free Europe, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 99: 1)
  - Romania. Legatia (Sweden), 1943-1947. (Folder 99: 2-3)
    Includes copies of telegrams sent to the U.S. State Department concerning the activity of George Duca during the Second World War (a set of copies exists also in the Romanian National Archives); codes for Duca's correspondence with Romania while at the Romanian Legation in Stockholm; writings (by Duca?) on the Allied-Romanian negotiations, 1943-1944; and a business card of Ambassador Alexandra Kollontay
  - Stanford University
    - General, 1976-1981 (Folder 99: 4)
    - Advisors' handbook (Folder 99: 5)
    - Letters of recommendation for students, 1978-1985 (Folder 99: 6)
    - Notes on the seminars George Duca taught at Stanford University, 1976-1977 (Folder 99: 7-14)
    - Notes on the seminars George Duca taught at Stanford University, 1978-1981 (Folder 100: 1-16)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1819-1985 (Box 101)
  - Alecsandri, Vasile. (Folder 101: 1)
    Includes one of his letters to Efcaria Duca, n.d. (19th century)
  - Duca, Ion G. - Memoirs (Amintiri politice), 1981-1982
    - Correspondence of George Duca pertaining to the publication of his father's political memoirs, a proof-reading copy of the first volume, and newspaper articles reviewing I. G. Duca's memoirs (Folder 101: 2-4)
    - Printed copies of the memoirs (Folder 101: 5-7)
  - Marie, Queen, Consort of Ferdinand I, King of Romania. (Box 102)
    Letters to Lavinia Small
    - 1933-1934 (Folder 102: 1)
    - 1935-1937 (Folder 102: 2)
  - Religion. Bible and religious brochures given by Princess Ileana to George Duca, 1950-1985 (Folder 102: 3-4)
  - Romania (Box 103)